### Joshua Stowers

#### Fullstack Engineer

Stowers.Joshua@live.com

August 2015 - June 2016

210-846-3998

Full stack developer with nearly 4 years of development experience. Persistent, detail-oriented, and highly adaptable. Self motivated to learn and expand beyond expectations. Currently seeking employment as a Ruby on Rails or React developer in a position that entails the continual acquisition of new skills.

unat entails the continual acquisition of new skills.

## Experience

Pressable

• Developed and maintained Rails 3 web app to help customers manage Wordpress sites

- Rewrote control panel to both display more relevant data and improve user experience
- Introduced Javascript solutions to address performance, feedback, and aesthetic issues
- Implemented background processing and caching strategies in order to handle large traffic effectively
- · Practiced test driven development with Rspec & Capybara to achieve full test coverage of the code base
- Developed proprietary, server-side automation tools and APIs in PHP

HipSTU May 2015 - August 2015

- Worked with small team to redesign and rebuild the full social E-commerce platform with Rails 4
- Improved application performance by over 5 times the original design

Stowers Solutions November 2012 - Present

- Developed and licensed "Stowers Solutions" for custom software consultancy
- · Managed multiple clients at a time, working with each to construct personalized, aesthetic, responsive websites
- · Automated deployment of PHP and Rails E-commerce sites with Ansible

Elevate Systems May 2013 - August 2013

- · Managed and revised clients' Joomla, Drupal, and Wordpress websites
- · Configured networked printers, workstations, stamp machines, and other devices

#### Tombstone Texas USA

May 2012 November 2012

- · Built custom PHP website to handle reservations, user-uploaded photos, and newsletter
- · Set up and configured POS system to handle transactions and order placements
- Handled communications with food and service providers, Groupon, and LivingSocial

## Projects

#### MissionSpree

• A Charitable E-commerce site leveraging both Rails and React simultaneously

#### **FamilyPhoneList**

· A cross-platform address-book app for keeping families organized, built with Meteor JS

#### Skills

HTML/HAML/ERB CSS/LESS/SASS JS/jQuery/CoffeeScript Node/React/Angular

Ruby/Rails/SinatraWordpress/Drupal/JoomlaLAMP StackELK StackMetasploitLets EncryptAnsible/ChefVMs/DockerShell/Bash/FishGit/Git WorkflowAgile/SCRUMStripe/BrainTreePythonPHPEnglish

# Education

#### Austin College, International Economics

2011 - 2015

- · Majors: International Economics, Business Finance, German
- · Nine months study abroad, Marburg, Germany